Finding Aid to the Margaret Sanger papers SSC.MS.00138
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE AND RELATED MATERIAL, 1877-1983
  - Grierson, Margaret, 1949-66 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Griessemer, Thomas O., 1954-56 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Gyanee, Bhagwan, 1938; undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - G, 1923-60 (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
  - Hamlin, Scoville, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Hastings, George A., 1937-38 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Henshaw, Paul S., 1952-54 (Box 30, Folder 12-13)
  - Higgins, Anna E. ("Nan"), 1910-44 (Box 30, Folder 14-16)
  - Higgins, Grant, 1942; 1948 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Higgins, Mary (includes journal, 1895-1900), 1891-1926 (Box 30, Folder 18-19a)
  - Higgins, Michael, 1900-18 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
  - Higgins, Richard and Mabel, 1925-58 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Higgins, Robert, 1913-58 (Box 30, Folder 23-24)
  - Higgins, Virginia ("Ginger"), 1943; 1948 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Himes, Norman E., 1931-38 (Box 30, Folder 26-27)
  - Holland-Rantos Company, 1944-50 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Holmes, John Hayes, 1938; 1953 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Holt, Rackham, 1936-40 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Hopkins, Prynce, 1958; 1962 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Hoppe, Joan Sanger, 1948; 1949 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Hornibrook, Ettie Rout, 1925-35 (Box 30, Folder 33-34)
  - Houghton, Vera, 1925-59 (Box 30, Folder 35-36)
  - How-Martyn, Edith, 1915-49 (Box 30, Folder 37-38)
  - Huse, Penelope B.P., 1936; 1943 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Huxley, Henry, 1938 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - H, 1915-63 (Box 30, Folder 41-42)
  - Ingersoll, Marion, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Ishimoto, Arata, 1937(?); 1938 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - I, 1915-60 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Mary Compton, 1938-49 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, R.W., 1941 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - J, 1939-60 (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
  - Kato, Baroness Shidzue Ishimoto, 1933-56 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - Kennedy, Anne, 1917-61 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Kerr, R.B., 1942 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Kingsbury, John, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Kitzweger, Ben and Emma, 1936; 1949 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Knopf, S. Adolphus, 1919-1940 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Kreupl, Anna, 1938; undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - K, 1917-61 (Box 31, Folder 16-17)
  - Lader, Lawrence, 1953-55 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Lafitte, Francoise Cyon, 1922-71 (Box 31, Folder 19-23)
  - Lansing, Elizabeth, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Larsen, Nils P., 1952; 1957 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Lasker, Mary and Albert, 1940-42 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Ledever, Ilse, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Lew, T.T., 1942; 1943 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Lewis, Joseph, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Lilley, Madeline C., 1949 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Little, Clarence Cook, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Long, Elizabeth Barstow, 1941; 1948 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Love, Florence, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - L, 1937-60 (Box 31, Folder 34-35)
  - Macaulay, Mary, undated (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - MacDonald, Agnus Snead, 1934-63 (Box 31, Folder 37-38)
  - Matthews, William R., 1949-58 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - McCormick, Katherine Dexter, 1954-59 (Box 31, Folder 40-41)
  - McKinnon, Edna Rankin, 1938-47 (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - McNamee, Dorothy, 1953; undated (Box 31, Folder 43)
  - Miller, Lois Mattox, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 44)
  - Mitchell, Daisy, 1934-59 (Box 31, Folder 45-46)
  - Mohleri, Gladys, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 47)
  - Moore, Hazel Z., 1933-47 (Box 31, Folder 48)
  - Morain, Mary and Lloyd, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Myers, Louise Chase, 1937; 1942 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - M, 1912-69 (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
  - Nelson, Mary B., 1940; 1941 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Neufeld, Norbert, 1938-42 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Newman, Elizabeth, 1940-59 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1936-41 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Nugent, Frank J., 1940-48 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - N, 1937-58 (Box 32, Folder 11-12)
  - O'Connor, Robert, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Ottesen-Jensen, Elise, 1953-60 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - O, 1921-57 (Box 32, Folder 15-16)
  - Packard, Arthur, 1937-38 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Page, Phyllis, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Palmer, Eileen, 1937; 1983 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Pincus, Gregory, 1953-59 (Box 32, Folder 20-21)
  - Pittman, Hobson, 1946-52 (Box 32, Folder 22-23)
  - Posner, Henriette, 1929-55 (Box 32, Folder 24-28)
  - Prager, Hedwig, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Protitch, Ludmilla, 1940-42 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Pulitzer, Leopold, 1939-40 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - P, 1932-64 (Box 32, Folder 32-33)
  - Rama Rau, Lady Dhanvanthi, 1951-57 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Reiland, Reverend Karl, 1931; 1943 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Remont, Ruby, 1940; 1946 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Richard, Olive Byrne, 1926-69 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Riese, Hertha, 1940-42 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Ripley, Katie Rice and George, 1936-40 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Rock, John, 1948-55 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
  - Rockefeller, Martha Baird and John D., Jr., 1949; 1955 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Rogers, Mabelle and George, 1946; 1956 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Rollins, Leighton, 1947-63 (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Roots, Margaret, 1957; 1959 (Box 33, Folder 14-15)
  - Rose, D. Kenneth, 1939-48 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Rose, Florence, 1931-66 (Box 33, Folder 17-21)
  - Roseberry, Eleanor, 1940; 1941 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Rublee, Juliet Barrett, 1922-58 (Box 33, Folder 23-25)
  - R, 1932-60 (Box 33, Folder 26-27)
  - Salter, Katherine, 1934-61 (Box 33, Folder 28-29)
  - Sanger, Barbara Peabody, 1948-60 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Sanger, Edwina, 1939; 1952 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Sanger, Grant, 1908-69 (Box 33, Folder 32-33)
  - Sanger, Peggy, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Sanger, Stuart, 1915-63 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
  - Sanger, William, 1914-52 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
  - Schoelkopf, Olive, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Schuman, Anna Jane Phillips, 1936-42 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Scribner, Charles Ezra, 1935; 1950 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Sideri, Marcella, 1926-32 (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
  - Simonds, Herbert R., 1940; 1948 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Slee, J. Noah H., 1889-1943 (Box 35, Folder 1-9)
  - Smith, Clarence L., 1941; 1942 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Stone, Abraham, 1936-59 (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
  - Stone, Hannah M., 1925-41 (Box 36, Folder 4-5)
  - Sunday Worker, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - S, 1915-62 (Box 36, Folder 7-8)
  - Tagore, Rubindranth, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Tallent, Roxie, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Toy, J.J., undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - T, 1932; 1940; undated (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
  - Union of East and West, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 14-15)
  - U, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Valiant, Margaret Mims, 1946-59(?) (Box 36, Folder 17-18)
  - van Buren, Helen, 1934-38 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Vandever, Martha, 1930-36 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1938; 1961; undated (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Vickery, Alice Drysdale, 1887-98 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Vogt, William, 1951-58 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Voorsanger, Henriette, 1937-49 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Voronoff, Liza and John, undated (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - V, 1937-54 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Wadia, Arabai B., undated (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Watumull, Ellen J., 1951-66 (Box 36, Folder 28-29)
  - Wells, H.G., 1944; 1946 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Wile, Ira Solomon, 1942; 1943 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - Williams, William, 1920; undated (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - W, 1920(?)-60 (Box 36, Folder 33-34)
  - YWCA, 1937-46 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - Zborowski, Hazel, 1935-38 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - Zonite Products Corporation, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 37)
  - Z, 1937; 1953 (Box 36, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified, 1907-94 (Box 36, Folder 39)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES, 1903-1966
  The organization records are arranged alphabetically by name of organization, and then sorted by category of material (minutes, reports, form letters, etc.) under each organization, and arranged chronologically under each category. The conference material has been organized chronologically by conference. Larger conferences have been broken down further by record type (programs, correspondence, proceedings, etc.).
  This series is very incomplete and deficient in key documents. Core organization and conference records such as board and major committee minutes, annual reports, and publications, releases, pamphlets and other material written by Sanger or directly related to her work have been incorporated in the microfilm edition. For more information on the Sanger related birth control organizations, see the organizational histories in the guide to The Margaret Sanger Papers Microfilm Edition: Smith College Collection Series.
  The organization materials that remain in the unfilmed collection include records of the major birth control organizations that Sanger was associated with: the American Birth Control League (ABCL), Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (BCCRB), Birth Control Federation of America (BCFL), Birth Control International Information Centre (BCIIC), International Committee on Planned Parenthood (ICPP), International Planned Parenthood Federation (IPPF), Margaret Sanger Research Bureau (MSRB), National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control (NCFLBC), Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA), and World Population Emergency Campaign (WPEC). A smaller group of records covers many of the other organizations that were vital to Sanger's work, including the ACLU, the AMA, the American Nurses Association, the Human Betterment Association, the New York City Department of Health, and the Population Reference Bureau, among many others; English organizations that worked closely with Sanger: the Malthusian League (includes writings by Alice Vickery and C.V. Drysdale) and the Eugenics Society; and two early birth control organizations that competed with Sanger: the National Birth Control League and the Voluntary Parenthood League. However, most of these files contain only a few pamphlets or a small amount of correspondence. Limited records of several foundations that supported Sanger's work are also contained in this series.
  For each of the major Sanger birth control organizations, the records are arranged in roughly the same order: general information, correspondence, minutes, organizational memos, publications, reports, form letters. Some of the organizations include other categories of material which are filed in a logical progression.
  Most of the ABCL records cover the years 1929-1939 when Sanger was not active in ABCL affairs (she resigned as president in 1928). The correspondence in the ABCL files contains many letters to and from NCFLBC staff as the two organizations discussed issues related to congressional lobbying efforts and fund-raising. The ABCL publications file includes reports on and articles about the Birth Control Review, which was published under the auspices of the ABCL starting in 1923. All other records of the Review from the Sanger collection have been incorporated in the microfilm edition.
  The BCCRB records (1928-1939) include useful statistical reports on clinic patients (many of these monthly reports are summarized in annual reports incorporated in the microfilm edition), some of Florence Rose's field reports (many more reports are contained in the Florence Rose papers in the Sophia Smith Collection) conducted in conjunction with the NCFLBC, and a study on the Recreation Rooms and Settlement Birth Control Clinic (1933-1935), a satellite clinic located in the tenement district of New York's Lower East Side. Records of the BCCRB's Harlem Branch (1930-1936) are included in a separate grouping and provide more detail than parallel records in the microfilm edition. For clinic records prior to 1928 (when the clinic operated under the auspices of the ABCL), see information regarding the Clinical Research Bureau in the ABCL files. Additional records are located under the NCFLBC (the two organizations shared staff and conducted joint fund-raising projects).
  The records of the BCFA (1939-1942) include extensive publications, information on personnel, monthly reports submitted to the BCFA by the MSRB, and papers given at the 1941 annual meeting. The records also contain reports and correspondence related to the Division of Negro Services/Negro Project.
  A single folder on the BCIIC is comprised of publications distributed by the organization.
  A small amount of material is contained in the ICPP files (1948-1952). Most of the records duplicate what exists in the microfilm edition and concern efforts to consolidate the organization and organize a world conference in India in 1952 (at which the IPPF was formally established).
  The IPPF records span 1952 to 1964 and duplicate much of what is included in the microfilm edition. The files contain a number of drafts of constitutions and by-laws, committee minutes, publications chronicling the history of the international movement, regional and special subject reports, and conference programs. The unfilmed IPPF material includes comprehensive lists of members and representatives.
  The records of the MSRB (1940-1969) include detailed financial reports from the 1950s, considerable personnel information, and publications on the history of the clinic. Of particular interest are files containing transcripts of marriage counselling group sessions from 1946 to 1948. These transcripts, along with a small amount of correspondence, consist of very frank discussions about sexual dysfunction and achieving sexual compatibility. There is also a folder on proposals for a Margaret Sanger Memorial building and a group of photographs of the clinic. Some of the documents, the minutes in particular, are duplicated in the microfilm edition.
  The NCFLBC records (1929-1938) contain a large correspondence file, including a series of letters from the fund-raising consultants Tamblyn & Tamblyn; extensive reports on field work and lobbying activities; financial reports; proceedings of Congressional hearings; and collections of endorsements, statements and speeches in favor of birth control. In particular, the reports from individual field workers and lobbyists document the aims and agendas of the organization and provide material that is not always condensed in summary and yearly reports located in the microfilm edition. Some of the NCFLBC records overlap with BCCRB material since the two organizations shared staff members and pursued joint projects.
  Records of the PPFA (1942-1966) make up the largest group of organizational records in the unfilmed Sanger collection, but offer many documents that are available in the two microfilmed collections of Sanger's papers, as well as in the voluminous PPFA collection in the Sophia Smith Collection. The bulk of these files consist of committee minutes from the 1950s and 1960s and communications with affiliate organizations. There is minimal correspondence and noticeable gaps in the material covering the 1940s. A relatively complete run of budget and expense reports exists for the late 1950s. Notable among these records is an extensive publications file comprised of both propaganda materials and practical advice manuals, including a comic book, "Escape from Fear."
  The limited WPEC records (1960-1962) include correspondence primarily related to fund-raising; documents outlining the organization's close alignment with the IPPF and merger with PPFA; newsletters and copies of IPPF's Around the World News of Population and Birth Control (a complete run is available in the Sophia Smith Collection); and several key reports, including a "Preliminary Survey of the Population Problems and Family Planning Programs in Africa, Asia, and the Western Hemisphere," and travel reports on Asia written by George and Barbara Cadbury.
  The WPEC and PPFA records overlap to some extent since the organizations merged in 1961. Documents produced under the merged name of PPFA- WPEC can be found in the records of both organizations, although the preponderance of this material is filed under PPFA. The IPPF records also contain material related to WPEC, which served as a fund-raising vehicle for IPPF projects.
  Information on regional and state or country clinics or organizations is located in SERIES V. COUNTRIES AND REGIONS.
  The conference files span 1903 to 1960 and include documentation of small, regional conferences and major world population conferences. Core records have been incorporated in the microfilm edition. While there is some duplication between the filmed and unfilmed collections, the records here include documentation of the many contributions made by organizers of the conferences apart from Sanger.
  The early conference records consist primarily of proceedings, many of which were published. The files on the 1927 World Population Conference in Geneva contain several conference publications not included in the microfilm edition, along with photographs and a scrapbook containing cards of many of the participants. Records of the Seventh International Birth Control Conference in Zurich in 1930 include transcriptions of a large number of conference speeches. Files on the international planned parenthood conferences in 1952, 1953, 1955, 1957 (proposed) and 1959, offer substantial coverage of the events in the form of programs, clippings, speech transcriptions and proceedings, as well as correspondence on the organization of the conferences and lists of sponsors, contributors and conference delegates. Copies of some of the published conference proceedings can also be found in Sanger's library (SERIES VII. PRINTED MATERIAL).
  - American Birth Control League
    - General, 1921-38 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1922-38 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1937 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Publications
      - Pamphlets and clinic literature, 1925-38 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Birth Control Review, 1929-35 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Reprints, 1926-38 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Reports
      - General, 1925-35 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - James F. Cooper, 1926 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Forms, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau
    - General, 1930-38 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1929-39 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 1937-38 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Reports
      - General, 1928-39; undated (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
      - Contributions, 1928-29 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Florence Rose, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Patient consultation, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Recreation Rooms and Settlement Birth Control Clinic, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Abstracts, 1938 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Press releases, 1938; undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Personnel, 1931-35 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Form letters, 1936; 1938; undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Contraceptive instruction, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Photographs, undated ( 1930s) (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Harlem Branch Clinic
      - Correspondence, 1931-36 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Reports (Box 38)
        - General, 1930-32 (Box 38, Folder 15)
        - Monthly, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 16)
        - Financial, 1932 (Box 38, Folder 17)
        - Clippings, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Birth Control Federation of America
    - General, 1939-42 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1939-42 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Division of Negro Service/Negro Project, 1939-41 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Organizational memos, 1940 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Publications
      - Pamphlets and brochures, 1940-41 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Reprints, 1938-41 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Reports
      - General, 1940-42 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Division of Negro Service/Negro Project, 1940-43 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Annual meeting papers, 1940-42 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Monthly clinic reports (BCCRB/MSRB), 1939-42 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Form letters, 1940 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Affiliated clinic literature, forms, and cards, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Abstracts, 1939-41 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Forms, 1941; undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1941; 1942 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Photographs, 1942; undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Birth Control International Information Centre, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - International Committee on Planned Parenthood
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Reports, 1948-52 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - International Planned Parenthood Federation
    - General, 1952-58 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Aims and objectives, constitutions, and by-laws, 1953-54 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1953-64 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Minutes, 1953-64 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Organizational memos, 1954-64 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Publications, 1955-62 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Reports (Box 40)
    - General, 1953-61 (Box 40, Folder 10-11)
    - Financial, 1953-61 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Conference programs, 1957-64 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Member lists, 1952-62 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1953-55 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Activities (photostatic copies) (Box 40, Folder 17)
      [see Flat File]
  - Margaret Sanger Research Bureau
    - General, 1940-60 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1940-66 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Twenty year anniversary pamphlet, 1943-46 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Staff memos, 1941-48 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1940-46 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 1943-63 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Reports
      - General, 1942-70 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Financial statements and budgets, 1950-61 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Marriage counselling group sessions, 1946-48 (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
    - Press releases, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Form letters, 1962-63 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Personnel, 1943; undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Invitations, 1959-61 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Schedules, 1960-61 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Margaret Sanger Memorial, 1967-69 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Photographs, 1944-46; undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control
    - General, 1929-38 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1930-38 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Helen Countryman Gracey, 1936-37 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Tamblyn and Tamblyn (professional fund raisers), 1934-36 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1930; 1936 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Publications
      - General, 1929-38 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Reprints, 1928-35 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Clippings and magazine articles, 1935-37 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Newsletters, 1930-36 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Press releases, 1932-37 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Reports
      - General
        - 1929-35 (Box 42, Folder 11)
        - 1936-38 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Financial statements and budgets, 1930-36 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Treasurer, 1935-36 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Contribution lists, 1929-32 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Field work, 1932-38 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Legislative reports, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Form letters, 1933-36 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Endorsements, 1934-36 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Statements in support of birth control, 1932-34 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, 1931-36 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Hearings, 1932-35 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America
    - General, 1943-63 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1942-61 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Constitution, by-laws, 1962; undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Minutes
      - Research committees, 1956-61 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Affiliates committee, 1959-62 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Executive committee, 1944; 1957 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Field committee, 1948-57 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Medical committee, 1946-61 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1951-59 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Publications
      - "The Anatomy of a Victory", 1959 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Comic books, 1956; 1962 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - General, 1942-66 (Box 45, Folder 3)